Guide to the Graduate School of Political Management political advertisement videocassette collection, 1970-2005 MS2241.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Political advertisements, 1970-2002; MS2241 Series 1; 10.5 Linear feet
  - Nixon Speeches, "Republican Leadership at the Grassroots," RNC 1980 Spots (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Note: This advertisement is on the video in box 11 tape number 20. It contains speeches by President Nixon and Republican National Committee advertisements.
  - Political Communications (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Advertisement produced by Arnold & Associates. Includes: Pacific Power, Driver Project, The Chronicle and Examiner, Pacific Gas and Electric, Ballot Initiative 4, Bush/Quayle '92.
  - Political Communication and Social Responsibility (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Advertisement produced by Argumento.
  - Political Demo (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Advertisement produced by Paul Kinney Productions.
  - Political Marketing: A Brazilian Experience in Democracy (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Presentation Reel (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Advertisement produced by The Media Team. Includes: McConnell "Lease of Life," Taft "Sayonara," Taft "Travels II," Branstad "Family/Future," McConnell "Harvey's Pills," Kean "Bandwagon," Kean "Sketch," Branstad "Solid Future," Gramm "Ken Scott," Gramm "Social Security," Humphry "Mildred Ingham," McConnell "Bankrupt," McConnell "Hound Dogs," Bush-Quayle 88 "Tank," Bush-Quayle 88 "Family/Children."
  - Presentation Reel (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Advertisement produced by Sipple Strategic Communications.
  - Argumento Promotional Video (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Sample Polticial TV Spots, Dueling Candidates, and Advocacy and Ballot Measures (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Advertisement produced by Nordlinger Associates.
  - Sixty Second Spot (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Advertisement produced by The Image Makers.
  - Socal Security (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Advertisement produced by Democratic Congressional Campaign Committee.
  - TRG Demo Domestic (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Winning! Campaign Commercials that Work (Box 7, Folder 29)
    Advertisement produced by Lazlo & Associates, Inc.
  - Your Voice (Box 7, Folder 30)
    Note: Russian language advertisement.
- Broadcast programming, 1984-2005; MS2241 Series 2; 2.5 Linear feet
  The videos of this series include local and network news reports, political talk shows, television newsmagazines, special reports, interviews and other broadcast programming. They range in date from 1984-2005 with some undated videos. The bulk of the series covers 1988-2000.
  - Evening News, 10/04/1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - News Report on the Graduate School of Public Management, 10/01/1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - ABC "This Week", 08/28/1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Note: video originally titled "Brinkley, Worthington, Edda Williams, Jackson."
  - Nightline: Campaign '88 with Jeff Greenfeild., 09/12/1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Presidential Politics, 09/19/1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Note: video originally titled "McLaughlin Group."
  - News on Ltw Ads, 10/19/1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Voter Turnout, 11/06/1988 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - '88 Election Eve, Dukakis and Bush Final Statement, PBS "The Last Word", 11/07/1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Election '88 and America's Political Parties, 11/1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Includes: "Democrats," "48 Hours" (Gun Control Referendum), and "Great Upset of '48" (Truman/Dewey).
  - Rather/Bush, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Includes: CBS News report on the Iran-Contra Scandal and Bush/Dukakis advertisements.
  - Buddy Roemer, Governor of Louisiana C-Span Interview, 9/1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Moyer's "The Public Mind", 11/1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Includes: "Consuming Images" and "Leading Questions."
  - Racism in America, 01/15/1990 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Connie Chung Exxon, 07/10/1990 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Campaigning for the Presidency, Road to the White House, 01/17/1992-01/19/1992 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Democratic Presidential Debate, Road to the White House, 02/16/1992 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Note: This news program is on the video in box 12 tape number 14. It contains Democratic Presidential Debates and the program "Road to the White House."
  - C-Span Segment, 10/14/1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - ABC Nightline Special "72 Hours to Victory", 11/05/1992 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - News/GSPM, 04/05/1994 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - WRC-TV Local News and ABC Network News, 04/12/1994 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Power of the People, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - News, 04/17/1995 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - News Coverage, 04/24/1995 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Edited News Elements, 05/1995 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - The Kalb Report: Campaign '96, 02/1996 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - 1996 Republican Convention (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Note: video originally titled "Adaptive Filtering and Control."
  - GSPM News, 04/14/1997 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    Includes: Sex/Military local, Sex/Military national, Guns/Babies national, Guns/Babies local.
  - GSPM News, 04/21/1997 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    Includes: NBA/Kids national, NBA/Kids local, Kick Butts local, Kick Butts national.
  - Sunday Morning "Ready, Set, Spin", 04/05/1998 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Channel 9, 01/19/1999 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Campaign 2000 Predictions, 10/30/2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The Clinton Years, 01/2001 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - WRC-TV NBC4 Local Newscast, 04/16/2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - ABC Network News with Peter Jennings, 04/16/2001 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - WRC-TV (Ch 4), 04/18/2005 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - WRC News, 04/25/2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - WRC News and ABC News, 05/25/2005 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - WRC-TV Local News and ABC Network News (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Arizona Consumer Insurance Coalition (Box 9, Folder 10)
    These news programs are on the video in box 9 tape number 10. It contains political advertisements and news reports compiled by the Arizona Consumer Insurance Coalition, including: No on 201, People for Fair Insurance, Billboard; No on 201, People for Fair Insurance, Blackboard; Yes on 201, Arizona Policyholders Association, Powell; Yes on 201, Arizona Policyholders Association, Rolling Words; No on 105, Arizona Alert, Ralph Nader; News, 201 Lawsuit Coverage; News, KAET Opinion Survey/Powell Commentary (as Policyholders Association); News, Harvey Rosenfeld Press Coverage; News, Richard Weibe/AC/IC Telephone Bank.
  - "20/20" Report on Michael Donald Lynching Case, "West 57th Street" Boradcast about the KlanWatch's Lawsuit Against the North Carolina Klan's Paramilitary (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Panel Discussion on Roe v. Wade with Tom Brokaw (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Abortion: The New Civil War" and "The Final Days" (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Note: This video contains a Fox news panal on abortion and a movie about Nixon's final days as president.
  - CBS Image Promos (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Note: This local news report is on the video in box 6 tape number 26. It contains advertisements and a local news report.
  - Tax and Bear/Mondale Piece (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - NBC Roe v. Wade Special (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - WRC Newscast (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - NBC, ABC Newscast (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - The Power Game "The Unelected" (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Alan on "Politically Incorrect" (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Moyer's The Public Mind (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Political education, 1987-2000; MS2241 Series 3; 3.5 Linear feet
  The videos of this series include educational programming on the political process, panel discussions and lectures on political topics, recordings of political seminars and institutes, documentaries produced by interest groups, focus groups and viewer call-in shows. They range in date from 1987-2000 with some undated videos. The bulk of the series covers 1987-1995. Most of the programming relates to the political process, the profession of politics or specific political issues. Seminar and institute recordings include the American University Campaign Institute, New York State Library Seminar Series, North Carolina Institute of Political Leadership, Campaign Management Institute, Columbia University Seminars on Media and Society and Graduate School of Political Management classes and forums.
  - TIME Focus Group Interviews, 06/1987 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Includes: Group A: 21-29, Mixed, without Time; Group B: 21-29, Mixed, with Time; Group C: 16-20, Women, with Time.
  - TIME Focus Group Interviews, 06/1987 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Includes: Group D: 16-20, Women, without Time; Group E: 30-50, Mixed, without Time; Group F: 30-50, Mixed, with Time; Group G: 16-20, Men, without Time.
  - Black Republicans & Elections, 10/28/1987 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Speech entitled "Impact of Black Republicans on Elections" presented by the Council of 100.
  - News, Politics and Ethics, 11/06/1987 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Panel entitled "News, Politics and Ethics: Political Journalists and Campaign Strategists" presented by the American Association of Political Consultants.
  - Polling and the Press, 11/06/1987 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Panel entitled "Polling: Why Does Press Focus on the Horserace and End Up Picking the Wrong Horse?" presented by the American Association of Political Consultants.
  - Getting Women into Office, 11/20/1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Panel entitled "Getting Women Into Elective and Appointed Office" presented by the National Women's Conference Committee.
  - Campaign Elements, 01/05/1988 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Part of the American University Campaign Institute
  - Research Overview, Survey Research and Political Ethics: Tape 1 of 2, 01/06/1988 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Research Overview, Survey Research and Political Ethics: Tape 2 of 2, 01/06/1988 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Campaign Communications and the Media: Tape 1 of 2, 01/12/1988 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Campaign Communications and the Media: Tape 2 of 2, 01/12/1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - How to Establish Good Relations with the Press and Party as a Campaign Resource: Tape 1 of 2, 01/15/1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - How to Establish Good Relations with the Press and Party as a Campaign Resource: Tape 2 of 2, 01/15/1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Party as a Campaign Resource: Tape 2 of 2, 01/15/1988 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Management, 04/07/1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Speech entitled "Campaign Management: Spring Training '88 Campaigns and Elections."
  - Legislative Intent, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Part of the New York State Library Seminar Series.
  - Polling Tape, 07/01/1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Panel entitled "On Polling" presented by the Washington Times.
  - Political Fundraising, 08/15/1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Viewer call-in show entitled "Roundtable with Republican Fundraisers."
  - Opposition Research and Tactics, 09/16/1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Lobbying in Washington, 12/11/1988 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Viewer call-in show entitled "Process and Policy."
  - Media Ads and Strategies, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Panel entitled "Media Advertising and Strategies: From Iowa to the White House."
  - "Justice on Furlough," Campaign to Preserve a Conservative U.S. Senate, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Nine Broadcast Plaza-Governor Cuomo with GSPM Students, 01/05/1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Report to the Board of the IOPL Fellows of Spring 1991 Class, 11/1990 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Part of the North Carolina Institute of Political Leadership
  - Road to the White House, 12/27/1990-01/05/1991 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Campaign Management Institute
  - Road to the White House, 01/11/1992 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - The Changing Political Landscape, 10/26/1992 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    A GSPM Forum
  - "Congress at the Crossroads," Perot advertisement, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Panel entitled "Congress at the Crossroads" presented by the House Legislative Assistants Association. Note: This video also contains a biographical advertisement of Ross Perot.
  - Policy and Election Jury Descriptions, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Soroson Talk, 01/31/1995 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    Lecture on speech writing by Ted Sorenson.
  - GSPM Speechwriting Lecture-Ted Sorenson: Tape 1 of 2, 01/31/1995 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - GSPM Speechwriting Lecture-Ted Sorenson: Tape 2 of 2, 01/31/1995 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - The X Factor: A GSPM Panel, 04/06/1995 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - 100 Days Panel, 04/10/1995 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    Panel on the first 100 days of the 104th Congress, with Clift, Goeas, Hart, Kondracke, Arterton.
  - Third Party/Independent Panel, 06/02/1995 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    Panel entitled "Third Party Candidates and the 1996 Election" presented by the Graduate School of Political Management, with Roberts, Weicker, Evans, Anderson, Kohut and Arterton.
  - Strategic Factors in Presidential Elections "Primaries and Caucuses", 09/18/1995 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    Panel entitled "Primaries and Caucuses," with Dayton Duncan, Ken Pins, Tom Oliphant, Maxine Isaacs and Jim Pinkerton.
  - Strategic Factors in Presidential Elections "The Media", 10/09/1995 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Panel entitled "The Media," with Hess, Apple, McCurry, Clark.
  - Primaries and Caucuses, 02/23/1996 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Proclaiming Your Vision, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    Produced by GOPAC, The Education and Training Center for Renewing America.
  - Bearing Witness: Making Democracy Work, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Political Consultants: Who Are They and What Do They Really Do?, 04/12/2000 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - AAPC Tape 2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Panel commentary presented by the American Association of Political Consultants.
  - The Art of Giantkilling: Dos and Don'ts for Public Interest Advocates (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Campaigning to Win: A Step by Step Guide to a Winning Election" (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Note: video originally titled "Push Play to Win."
  - Cleaning Up (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Cleaning the Air (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Five-part Video News Release Series, including: Overview/Progress, Mobile Sources, Air Toxics, Acid Rain, Ozone Pollutions.
  - Cuomo Focus Group (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Including: Corruption, Angry, Good News.
  - Democracy and Rights: One Citizen's Challenge (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Ethics in America (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Note: video originally incorrectly also titled "Power Game." Part of the Columbia University Seminars on Media and Society.
  - Ethics in America: Part III (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Part of the Columbia University Seminars on Media and Society.
  - Fires of Freedom (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Produced by Citizens for America Educational Foundation.
  - Head Start Now! (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Produced by the Children's Defense Fund.
  - Electronic Focus Group (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Making Legislators Accountable (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Produced by the AFL-CIO.
  - National Museum of the American Indian National Campaign (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Professional Signature Gatherers (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Presidential Campaign Structure: The New Technologies (Box 11, Folder 16)
    A GSPM panel with Fouhy, Phillips, Strobel, Isaacs, Pinkerton.
  - Campaigns and Elections (Box 11, Folder 17)
    An educational documentary entitled "Prime-time Politics: New Directions in Political TV Advertising."
  - The Religious Right in the Center (Box 11, Folder 18)
    A GSPM Forum on Politics
  - Time Magazine Focus Group (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Speeches and debates, 1980-2000; MS2241 Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet
  The videos of this series include campaign and political speeches, candidate debates, political party conventions and awards ceremonies. They range in date from 1980-2000 with some undated videos. The bulk of the series covers 1984-1996. The majority of these videos focus on national politics, including presidential elections.
  - Nixon Speeches, "Republican Leadership at the Grassroots," RNC 1980 Spots (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Note: This video also contains Republican National Committee advertisements.
  - 1982 NY Governor Debates and Appearances, 09/16/1981 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Includes: Inside Albany, NY Post Debate, Gabe Pressman, "Brinkley," Daily News Debate, and Lehrman on CBS News.
  - Lew Lehrman Spots, Lehrman Demo, Mario Cuomo-State of the State Address, Lehrman/Cuomo Debate, 10/07/1982 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Note: These speeches and debates are on the video tape in box 1 tape number 4. It contains advertisements for Lew Lehrman, Mario Cuomo's State of the State address and a debate between Lehrman and Cuomo.
  - Dartmouth Presidential Debate, 01/05/1984 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Mario Cuomo Democratic National Convention Speech, 07/16/1984 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Mario Cuomo 1984 Democratic Convention, Inside Albany Cuomo/Lehrman (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Republican National Convention, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - 1984 Presidential Debate (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Reagan-Mondale Presidential Debate, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - 1987 Presidential Firing Line Debates (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Presidential End Hunger Awards, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Election '88 Democratic Debate: Tape 1, 02/18/1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Election '88 Democratic Debate: Tape 2, 02/18/1988 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Presidential Forum (Democrats): Part 1, 02/19/1988 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Presidential Forum (Democrats): Part 4, 02/19/1988 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Michael Dukakis/Jesse Jackson California Debate, 05/25/1988 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Weicker/Lieberman, Dukakis/Bush, Lieberman/Weicker, 10/12/1988-10/18/1988 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Democratic National Convention Video Button, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Democratic National Convention Video Button, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Democratic National Convention, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - George Bush Speech, 1988 Republican National Convention (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Lieberman-Weicker Debates II and III, 03/03/1989 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - New Jersey Gubernatorial Debate Courter v. Florio, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - 1991 Gubernatorial Debate, FDR Film (Box 12, Folder 13)
    Note: This video also contains a movie about Franklin Delano Roosevelt.
  - Democratic Presidential Debate, Road to the White House, 02/16/1992 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Note: This video also contains the broadcast program "Road to the White House."
  - Maryland Democratic Candidates Debate, PBS-David Duke, 03/01/1992-03/02/1992 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Quayle Convention Video, 08/20/1992 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Perot Second Ad, Presidential Debate, 10/09/1992-10/15/1992 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Debate Aznar-Gonzalez, 05/24/1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Note: Spanish language debate
  - Debate Aznar-Gonzalez, 05/31/1993 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - State of the Union-Clinton, 01/24/1995 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Clinton State of the Union, 01/24/1995 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Convention, 09/16/1996 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    GOPTV Republican National Convention
  - The State of Political Consulting, 09/17/1996 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    Address by Democratic Political Strategist James Carville
  - Clinton-Dole Debate, 10/06/1996 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Gore/Bush, Lieberman/Cheney, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Congressman Cummings Speaks to Boergers' Fundamentals of Political Management Class, 11/2001 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Dean Arterton Welcome Remarks (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Democratic National Convention (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - The Speeches of Dwight D. Eisenhower (Box 12, Folder 29)
- Movies and documentaries, 1986-1996; MS2241 Series 5; 1 Linear feet
  The videos of this series include movies and documentaries on political topics. They range in date from 1986-1996 with several undated videos. The bulk of the series were produced from 1989-1992. Most of the movies are about presidents and the political process.
  - 1776, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - :30 Second Democracy: A Documentary on Political Television Advertising, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Backstage at the White House (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Campaigning for the Presidency, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Fabulous Fifties: Vol. 1 1950-54, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1991 Gubernatorial Debate, FDR Film (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Note: This movie is on the video in box 12 tape number 13. It contains a 1991 gubernatorial debate and movie about Franklin Delano Roosevelt.
  - "Abortion: The New Civil War" and "The Final Days" (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Note: This movie is on the video in box 9 tape number 13. It contains a Fox news panal on abortion and a movie about Nixon's final days as president.
  - First Ladies, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Great Figures in History-JFK (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Inside the White House, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Portraits of Heroes (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Rachel Carson Video (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Reagan's Way (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Sixties Headlines (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Stand-Up Reagan (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Television and the Presidency (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Tribute to Guy Vander Jagt, 10/14/1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)